Alessandro Simoni

PhD Student @ Department of Engineering "Enzo Ferrari"

Modena, Italy

C +39 334 8040595 | ■ alle.simoni.as@gmail.com | 🛪 alexj94.github.io | 🖬 LinkedIn | 🎓 Google Scholar

Summary _

I'm a PhD student under the tutorship of Prof. Roberto Vezzani at the International Doctorate School in ICT (Unimore, Italy) with the following research topic: "Computer Vision and Artificial Intelligence for Collaborative Robotic Environments".

My main interests are in Human-centric AI and Robotics exploiting deep learning and computer vision techniques applied to the 3D world. My research skills are related to 3D pose estimation of articulated objects and 3D object reconstruction through neural rendering techniques. I am also collaborating on a project related to the 3D reconstruction of vehicles through NeRF approaches.

Knowledge and computer skills _____

Programming languages Python (proficiency), C++, JavaScript **Libraries and Tools** PyTorch, NumPy, OpenCV, PyCharm

Domains Deep Learning, 2D/3D Computer Vision, 3D Human/Robot Pose Estimation, 3D Reconstruction

Spoken languages Italian mothertongue, English C1 (certifed ESOL Cambridge)

Working experiences _____

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Research grant July 2023 - (July 2024)

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

Project: "Al platform with digital twins of interacting robots and people"

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Research grant June 2022 - June 2023

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

Project: "Study of recent combinations of CNN and Vision Transformer architectures"

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Research grant May 2020 - May 2022

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

Project: "PREVUE - Prediction of Activities and Events by Vision in an Urban Environment"

Modena, Italy

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Student internship for master's degree thesis **Supervisor**: Prof. Rita Cucchiara

July 2019 - Feb. 2020

"Future urban scene generation: a deep learning approach for a 3D temporal vehicle reconstruction starting from monocular images"

Education _____

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

PhD student - Curriculum "Computer engineering and science"

Nov. 20

Nov. 2020 - (Mar. 2024)

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Master's degree in computer engineering

Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2020

• GPA: 27.806/30. Final grade: 108/110

Modena, Italy

1

Bachelor's degree in computer engineering

Sep. 2013 - Feb. 2017

• GPA: 23.607/30. Final grade: 91/110

October 8, 2023 Alessandro Simoni - resume

Certifications _

Certifications	
First Certificate in English (FCE)	
Grade A (Score 180, C1), University of Cambridge ESOL Examinations	Dec. 2020
Italian State certification exam for Engineer Profession	
Association of Engineers	2021
4^{th} Advanced Course on Data Science and Machine Learning (ACDL 2021) Participation certificate with final exam	July 2021
16^{th} International Computer Vision Summer School (ICVSS 2022) Participation certificate with final exam	July 2022
ELLIS Summer School on Large-Scale AI for Research and Industry Participation certificate with final project (NeRF-based camera optimization)	Sept. 2023
Additional information	
Citizenship Italian, German	
Travelling Passport, B license, own car	
Selected publications	
Complete list on Google Scholar.	
<u>Journals</u>	
Pattern Recognition Letters A.D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani, R.Cucchiara "Depth-based 3D human pose refinement: Evaluating the refinet framework"	Mar. 2023
Informatics A. D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "Multimodal hand gesture classification for the human-car interaction"	Aug. 2020
Conferences	
23^{rd} International Conference on Image Analysis and Processing D. Di Nucci, A. Simoni, M. Tomei, L. Ciuffreda, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "CarPatch: A Synthetic Benchmark for Radiance Field Evaluation on Vehicle Components"	Udine, Italy 11-15 Sept. 2023
35^{th} International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems + RA-L	Kyoto, Japan
A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani "Semi-Perspective Decoupled Heatmaps for 3D Robot Pose Estimation from Depth Maps"	23-27 Oct. 2022
9^{th} International Conference on 3D Vision	Virtual, Online
A. Simoni, S. Pini, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "Multi-category mesh reconstruction from image collections"	1-3 Dec. 2021
16^{th} VISIGRAPP	Virtual, Online
A. Simoni, A. D'Eusanio, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani "Improving car model classification through vehicle keypoint localization"	8-10 Feb. 2021
25 th International Conference on Pattern Recognition	Virtual, Online
A. Simoni, L. Bergamini, A. Palazzi, S. Calderara, R. Cucchiara "Future urban scene generation through vehicle synthesis"	10-15 Jan. 2021
8^{th} International Conference on 3D Vision	Virtual, Online
A. D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "A transformer-based network for dynamic hand gesture recognition"	25-28 Nov. 2020

According to law 679/2016 of the Regulation of the European Parliament of 27th April 2016, I hereby express my consent to process and use my data provided in this document and application for recruiting purposes.

"A transformer-based network for dynamic hand gesture recognition"

2